

Summary

I'm a PhD student at Universitat Pompeu Fabra under the joint supervision of Gemma Boleda and Laia Mayol. My PhD research currently focuses on understanding the use of referring expressions, mainly through quantitative and computational methods.

Education

Universitat Pompeu Fabra

Barcelona, Spain

Ph.D. candidate in Theoretical and Applied Linguistics

2019 - present

Universitat Pompeu Fabra

Barcelona, Spain

M.S. IN THEORETICAL AND APPLIED LINGUISTICS

2018 - 2019

• GPA: 8.68/10

• Venue: Computational Linguistics

Beijing Jiaotong University, Complutense University of Madrid

Beijing, China

B.S. IN HISPANIC PHILOLOGY

.5. IN HISPANIC PHILOLOGY

2014 - 2018

GPA: 9.58/10with Honors

Publication

Liao, X., Boleda, G., Mayol, L. (2021). Coherence-driven predictability and referential form: evidence from English corpus data. Proceedings of Sinn und Bedeutung 26, to appear.

Aina, L., **Liao**, X., Boleda, G., Westera, M. (2021, November). Does referent predictability affect the choice of referential form? A computational approach using masked coreference resolution. In Proceedings of the 25th Conference on Computational Natural Language Learning (pp. 454-469).

Presentation

UR-Ling workshop Barcelona, Spain

TALK

• Title: Referent predictability and referential choice

November 12th, 2021

September 9th. 2021

The SIGNLL Conference on Computational Natural Language Learning (CoNLL) 2021

Virtually

POSTER PRESENTATION

November 11th, 2021

- Title: Does referent predictability affect the choice of referential form? A computational approach using masked coreference resolution
- [PDF], [Poster]

Sinn und Bedeutung 26 Virtually

• Title: Coherence-driven predictability and referential form: evidence from English corpus data

Title. Conference-univers predictability and referential form. evidence from English Corpus dat

Workshop on Computational and Experimental Explanations in Semantics and Pragmatics

European Summer School in Logic, Language and Information (ESSLLI) 2021, Virtually

August 10th. 2021

TALK

TALK

• Title: Coherence-driven predictability and referential form: evidence from English corpus data

Student session in European Summer School in Logic, Language and Information (ESSLLI) 2021

Virtually

TALK August 6th. 2021

• Title: Coherence-driven predictability and referential form: evidence from English corpus data

November 21, 2021 Xixian Liao · Résumé



Semàntica i Pragmàtica (Professor: Martina Wiltschko)

Department of Translation and Language, Univeristat Pompeu Fabra

2020 - 2021

TEACHING ASSISTANT FOR MASTER COURSES

- Compositionality and Truth(conditions)
- Modality and possible worlds; Quantifiers
- · Clausal and nominal reference
- Presuppositions
- The Gricean program. Recognizing intentions.
- What we do when we use language: Speech act theory.
- Dynamic theories of meaning. Language in interaction.
- Expressing emotions and other non-truth-conditional meaning.
- The relation between language, thought and communication

Introducció a la Universitat i Recursos (Professor: Núria Bel)

Department of Translation and Language, Univeristat Pompeu Fabra

2020 - 2022

TEACHING ASSISTANT FOR UNDERGRADUATE COURSES

- Build an HTML website
- · Regular expressions
- · Corpus analysis

Work Experience _____

China's Commerce Ministry, Beijing Jiaotong University Training Center

Beijing, China

2017 - 2018

CHINESE-SPANISH INTERPRETER & TRANSLATOR IN SEMINARS FOR FOREIGN DELEGATIONS

Bilateral Seminar of Infrastructure Between China and Uruguay.

• Seminar On Ocean Railway Construction for Perú-Brasil

 Cielo Education
 Beijing, China

CHINESE TEACHER FOR FOREIGNERS

2017 - 2018

• Teaching elementary Chinese.

Fellowships_

2020.5-2023.5 FI Scholarship awarded by AGAUR (Agency for Management of University and Research Grants) 2019.9-2020.5 CSC Scholarship awarded by Chinese Scholarship Council

Languages & Skills

LANGUAGES Mandarin Chinese (native), English (IELTS C1), Spanish (DELE C1)
SKILLS Python, R, HTML, Visual Basic

Membership in Scientific Association

Association for Computational Linguistics (ACL)

2021 - present

November 21, 2021 Xixian Liao · Résumé 2